Guide to the George P. Garrett Papers, 1929-2008 (bulk 1960-2000)
George P. Garrett papers 1929-2008 (bulk 1960-2000)
- Accessions (2004-0133) and (2005-0067), 5 Boxes
  Additions (2005-0067) (1875 items, 3.0 lin. ft.; dated 1990s-2003) and (2004-0133) (2 items, 0.1 lin. ft.; dated 2004) comprise manuscripts, drafts, notes, typescripts, and correspondence for Double Vision, The Year in Fiction, and Every Bitter Thing. Also includes typescripts, notes, holograph manuscripts, and typescripts with holograph corrections for essays, stories, and other writings; and a broadside of Garrett's poem, Luck's Shinning Child, printed for the 2004 Virginia Festival of the Book.
  Closed pending processing.
  - Manuscripts and notes (Box 1)
  - Correspondence
  - The Year in Fiction
  - Miscellaneous manuscripts and notes (Box 2)
  - Double Vision drafts
  - Notes (Box 3)
  - Drafts
  - Reviews
  - Typescript of Double Vision (2004-0133)
  - Drafts and manuscripts (Box 4)
  - Every Bitter Thing
  - Drafts and manuscripts (Box 5)
  - Broadside: Luck's Shinning Child (2004-0133)
- Accession (2006-0090)
  The addition (750 items, 1.2 lin. ft.; dated 2005-2006) contains proofs for Bad Man Blues and The King of Babylon Shall Not Come Against You; manuscripts for Godfather and several short stories; print materials including books and journals authored or edited by Garrett; 2 DVD’s; and 12 diskettes.
  - DVDs: (Box 1)
    - Frankenstein Meets the Space Monster
    - Virginia Poets Laureate, 1996-2004
  - Manuscripts, typescripts, and proofs:
    - Talk at St. Paul's - Ivy
    - Laurence Stalling's Plume
    - An unpublished story
    - Bad Man Blues preprint layout draft
    - Godfather drafts
    - The King of Babylon Shall Not Come Against You preprint layout draft
  - Printed material:
    - Virginia Quarterly Review
    - Empty Bed Blues
    - Best New Poets, 2005
    - Nassau Literary Review
    - The Mint Julep
  - Manuscripts and typescripts: (Box 2)
    - The New Southern Writers
    - Hollywood Blues
    - The Title & All
    - Godfather
    - Front Matter
    - Towne in Tinseltown
    - The Inside Story of Frankenstein Meets the Space Monster
    - Boy Goes to Hollywood
    - Crossover Beard
  - Printed material:
    - The Sewannee Review, winter 2006, (2 copies)
- Accession (2007-0075)
  Addition (5,400 items; 7.2 lin. ft.; dated 1971-2006) primarily contains drafts of Garrett's writings as typescripts and electronic files on diskettes. Also included are books and journals that feature his works and works of other authors; audiocassettes and CDs of interviews and readings by Garrett; and correspondence. Closed pending processing.
  - Printed material: (Box 1)
    - Princeton Class of 1952 40th Reunion, June 1992
    - George Garrett: a Bibliography, 1947-1988, edited by Wright, 1989
  - Miscellaneous academic typescripts and manuscripts, 1987-2002
  - Photographs, (2 photographs)
  - Printed material:
    - Lillian Smith Awards, 1993
    - Sewanne Writers' Conference publications, 1990-2001
  - Elizabethan medal papers, 1999
  - Photograph - R.V. and Kay Cassill, Roma 1956 (Box 2)
  - Typescripts and drafts of Garrett's works
  - Periodicals and newspaper clippings
  - Printed material:
    - The Mint Julep by Harwell, 2005
    - New Millennium Writings: the Essence of George Garrett edited by Williams, 2003
    - George Garrett: the Elizabethan Trilogy edited by Horvath and Malin, 1998
    - The King of Babylon Shall not Come Against You by Garrett, 1996
    - Index 2005: Fellows and Residents at the American Academy in Rome, 2005
    - Mississippi Quarterly: the Journal of Southern Cultures, 2006
  - Manuscripts and typescripts: drafts of Garrett's works, 1990-2006 (Box 3)
  - Printed material: various literary publications, 1987-2004
  - Correspondence - personal, 1981-2006
  - Photograph series, (20 photographs)
  - 3.5" diskettes containing copies of Garrett's works, 2000-2005, (27 diskettes)
  - Audiocassettes:, (2 cassettes)
    - Fellowship of Southern Writers, University of Virginia, 1996
    - Garrett tribute, Balitimore, 2003
  - c-ville newspaper, 2002 (Box 4)
  - CD: Poet laureates reading
  - Audio of Garrett reading, c1982-c1994, (5 audiocassettes)
  - Printed material:
    - Four Virginia Poets Laureate, edited by Kreiter-Foronda and Lull
    - Film Scripts Two edited by Garrett, Hardison, Jr., and Gelfman, 1971
    - The Virginia Quarterly Review, winter 2005
    - The Sewanee Review, spring 2006
    - Mississippi Review, volume 34 number 3, 2006
  - DVD: Frankenstein Meets the Space Monster, 2006
  - Printed material: Sophocles, 2, edited by Slavitt and Bowie, 1998 (Box 5)
  - Typescripts:
    - Edited rough draft of Winning and Losing
    - Uncorrected proofs of Empty Bed Blues, 2005, (2 folders)
  - Periodicals and newspaper clippings, 1978-2006
  - Academic papers
  - 3.5" diskettes containing copies of Garrett's works, 2002-2003, (20 diskettes) (Box 6)
  - Periodicals and newspaper clippings
  - Printed material:
    - Ploughshares, volume 4 number 3, 1978
    - Meridian, fall 1999
    - The Georgia Review, fall/winter 2006
    - The Fictional World of William Hoffman by Frank, 2000
    - The Professions of Authorship: Essays in Honor of Matthew J. Bruccoli edited by Layman and Myerson, 1996
    - Ploughshares, volume 14 numbers 2&3, 1988
    - Ploughshares, winter 1999-2000
    - The Nassau Literary Review, fall-winter 2006
    - The Virginia Quarterly Review, spring 2002
    - Meridian, fall/winter 2002
    - The Carolina Quarterly, summer 1994
    - The Sewanee Review, spring 2003
    - Michigan Quarterly Review, fall 1996
  - Audiocassette: Fellowship of Southern Writers, University of Virginia, March 28, 1996
  - Printed material: Southern Writers; photographs by Spielman, text by Starr, 1997 (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous papers organized in envelopes
  - Periodicals and newspaper clippings
  - Typescripts and manuscripts: various notes and drafts of Garrett's works
  - Correspondence - personal and professional
  - CD of Garrett on NPR
  - Nametags and ribbons from events
  - Typescripts - various drafts of Garrett's works (Box 8)
  - Poster: 20th century poets
  - Virginia poet laureate certificate, 2002
  - Perdiodicals and newspaper clippings
  - Garrett's fraternity induction certificate, 1926
  - Photographs, (4 photographs)
  - Printed material:
    - Poets & Writers, July/August 2006
    - Willow Springs, fall 2006
    - Issues of The Sewanee Review, 2000, 2002
    - David Madden: a Writer for all Genres, edited by Hendricks and Perkins, 2006
    - Appalachia and Beyond, edited by Lang, 2006
    - The Silver Water Pitcher by Jiranek, 1988
  - Cassette tapes, 1996-2004
  - Typescripts: drafts of Garrett's works
  - Periodicals and newspaper clippings (Box 9)
  - Photographs, (8 photographs, 1 negative)
  - Printed material:
    - The Sewanee Review, 1996, 2005-2006, (7 issues)
    - Witness, 1991, 1992, 1996, (3 issues)
    - Black Warrior Review, fall/winter 1995
    - The Chattahoochee Review, summer 2006
    - A Quiet Pint in Kinvara by Tillinghast, 1991
    - Joy Writing by Amdahl, 2005
    - The Georgia Review, fall/winter 2006
    - Best New Poets: 2005, edited by Garrett and Livingwood
  - 3.5" diskettes containing copies of Garrett's works, 2005, (2 diskettes)
  - CD: News of the Spirit: the Storytelling of George Garrett, 2006
  - Typescripts of drafts of Garrett's works
  - Periodicals and newspaper clippings (Box 10)
  - Assorted items from Sewanna Military Academy 50th reunion, 1996
  - Photographs, (2 photographs)
  - Printed material:
    - Poetry, June 2006
    - New Literary History, volume 1 number 3, 1970
    - The Oxford Book of the American South: Testimony, Memory, and Fiction edited by Ayers and Mittendorf, 1997
    - The Writer's Chronicle, summer 2006
  - Printed material: (Box 11)
    - The World and I, April 1993
    - The Iron Mountain Review, spring 2006
    - The Girl in the Black Raincoat, 1982
    - Hill Ties, fall/winter 2006
    - Princeton Alumni Weekly, October 23, 1985
  - Typescripts and manuscripts including notes and drafts of Garrett's works.
  - CD: News of the Spirit: the Storytelling of George Garrett, 2006
  - Poster: Young Lovers
  - Correspondence - personal and professional
  - E-mail correspondence, 2006 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence - letter from John Carr, 2006
  - Correspondence - Willingham letter, 1989
  - Typescripts - purse permissions, 1992
  - Correspondence - personal and professional
- Accession (2008-0181)
  The addition (760 items; 1.2 lin. ft.; dated 1999-2008) contains notes, research, and drafts of Garrett’s short story The Source, eventually renamed Thanksgiving. There are also some folders of correspondence, transcripts of interviews, and some audiovisual material including four audiocassette tapes and one DVD.
  - Source: Roger Casement (Box 1)
  - Source: Angel Falls
  - Source: Long Steel Knives
  - Source: Photos, Dickey expedition
  - Source: Thanksgiving
  - Source notes, April 3, 2007
  - Source: Events
  - Source: Miscellaneous clippings
  - Source: Early draft
  - Source: Orinoco
  - Ciudad Bolivar
  - Source: News and headlines, 1931
  - Source: Miscellaneous notes
  - Ralegh Creature on Map
  - Venezuela flags
  - Source: Draft of Intro
  - Source: Epigraph
  - Source: Misc. notes on the Orinoco
  - Source: Draft, pages 1-21
  - Source: Early draft
  - National Geographic (Nov. 1933)
  - National Geographic (Nov. 1931)
  - Source: Possible ending draft
  - Source: Etc (notebook)
  - Source: Draft of ending
  - Garrett interviews (1-2)
  - Garrett interviews (3) (Box 2)
  - George Garrett poems
  - Correspondence
  - Source: Miscellaneous (unfoldered material)
  - George Garrett's birth certificate
  - 4 Audiocassettes
    - New Letters on the Air
    - John Ciardi: Speaking of Words
    - American Audio Prose Library readings
    - The King of Babylon Shall Not Come Against You partial reading
  - Key to the City of Knoxville
- Accession (2008-0271)
  The addition (375 items; 0.6 lin. ft.; dated 1985-2008) contains correspondence; drafts and notes for poems and other projects, including an Armies of Occupation project; and copies of newspaper clippings and interviews with Garrett.
  - Correspondence (Box 1)
  - Clippings and interviews, (2 folders)
  - Armies of Occupation: Thomas Dixon Jr.
  - Miscellaneous Notes for Armies of Occupation (notebook)
  - My summer reading etc. DLB
  - Armies of Occupation: Leftovers etc
  - Armies of Occupation: DLB
  - Armies of Occupation: Miscellaneous
  - Armies of Occupation: Ongoing
  - Armies of Occupation: Notes
  - Armies of Occupation: Notes and Source (notebook)
  - Armies of Occupation: Marines
  - Evangelista
  - Miscellaneous materials (unfoldered)
  - Hollins Conference notes
- Accession (2013-0168)
  Addition (Acc. 2013-0168) (50 items, 0.1 lin. ft.; dated 1964-1972) comprises a file of letters to Garrett from those whose last names begin with the letter "P."
  - Correspondence (Box 1)
  - to Garrett, Last name begins "P", (1 folder)